{
    "id": "c42d41ef6bb7496ca85b5c18d5da1382",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. of visiting America.",
            "description": "When think means ‘consider the idea of’, it is normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "think",
                "am thinking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………. ill since last week.",
            "description": "Perfect tenses are used with the time expressions since and for.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My dog is very silly he …………………………… after cats.",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used for a habitual action. The present continuous can also be used to talk about a particularly obstinate habit.",
            "answers": [
                "always runs",
                "is always running",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The steamer ………………………… yesterday.",
            "description": "To state that something happened sometime ago we use the simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "sailed",
                "has sailed",
                "is sailing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………….. anything from them for months.",
            "description": "Perfect tenses are preferred with the time expressions since and for.",
            "answers": [
                "hadn't heard",
                "haven't heard",
                "didn't hear"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I phoned her because I ……………………….. to talk.",
            "description": "Some verbs are never or hardly ever used in progressive forms. Want is one of them.",
            "answers": [
                "wanted",
                "was wanting",
                "have wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. his parents tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used here to indicate that the arrangement already exists.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "am seeing",
                "have seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. in ghosts?",
            "description": "Believe is one of those verbs that are not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "Do you believe",
                "Are you believing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I didn’t know how long she ………………………….. there.",
            "description": "The past perfect continuous tense is used to talk about an activity that had been going on around a past time. ",
            "answers": [
                "was sitting",
                "has been sitting",
                "had been sitting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The Rhine ……………………. into the North Sea.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense here because we are talking about a permanent situation.",
            "answers": [
                "has run",
                "runs",
                "is running"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When I reached home I noticed that water ……………………… down the wall.",
            "description": "We use the past continuous tense here to indicate that the situation was ongoing and temporary.",
            "answers": [
                "run",
                "was running",
                "has been running"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… her tastes, I sent her some flowers.",
            "description": "Although the verb know is not normally used in progressive tenses, it does have an –ing form which can be used in other kinds of structures.",
            "answers": [
                "Knowing",
                "Has known",
                "Known"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}